Professional and personal papers of Edwin Wolf 2nd LCP.EW2
Library Company of Philadelphia
- III. Scholarship, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
  - IIIb. Research, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
    - Fragonard: Letters between Edwin and D. Keppel and Deoch Fulton concering Edwin's article entitled “The Fragonard Plates for the Contes et Nouvelles of La Fontaine,” Bulletin of the New York Public Library LIII 107-120 [1949] (6 items), 1948 April 14-1949 March 26 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Benjamin Franklin: Research materials, typescript drafts, proofs, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Franklin medical books: Typescripts of articles regarding Franklin's medical library; letter to Edwin from Claude-Anne Lopez (Curator/Franklin Papers); offprint list of Franklin's medical books from Edwin's article, 1977 September 29, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Franklin medical books: Letter to Edwin from Beth Carroll; copies of documents related to the composition and dispersal of Franklin's medical library [circa 1789-24 October 1790], 1984 May 18, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Franklin medical books: Copies of documents related to the composition and dispersal of Franklin's medical library (6 items), undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Research files and notes (includes photocopies and photostats), 1912, 1921, 1965, 1967, 1970, 1971, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Correspondence, research files, and notes (includes thermofax, photocopies, and photostats), 1948, 1956-1960, 1974, 1983, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Various letters transcriptions, and notes, 1956-1984, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Correspondence regarding Wolf's requests for transcriptions and information verification for his catalogue, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "A," transcripts and photocopies of minutes and lists from the Athanaeum of Philadelphia, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "B," shipping label from The Book Farm, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "C," letter and photocopy of book title page from College of Physicians of Philadelphia, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "E," copies from microfilm of "Latest Revision of George Simpson Eddy's Catalogue of Dr. Franklin's Library", circa 1960 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "F," correspondence with Charles E. Feinberg, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "G," letter from Mrs. Walter Grossman at the Andover-Harvard Theological Library regarding their copy of Oceana, 1961 September 5 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "H," letter from Howell Heaney at the Free Library of Philadelphia and correspondence with King V. Hostick, 1961, 1963, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "M," various letters, notes, and thermofaxes, 1961, 1962, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "P-Q," letter and photocopy of letter from the Papers of Benjamin Franklin, 1959 January 28 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "S," letters to Charles Sellers, 1965 December (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "T-U-V," photocopy of list of materials held at the American Philosophical Society, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "W," correspondence with librarian at West Point, photostat of book cover, and press release regarding Franklin books found at West Point, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: "Y-Z," letter from Yale Medical Library, 1961 October 2 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Transcriptions and photostats of minutes from American Philosophical Society meetings in the 1800s, circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Research files and notes (includes photocopies and thermofax), 1989-1990, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Notes and lists regarding 1947 "Bache sale", undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Research files (includes photocopies and photostats), undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's library: Research files (includes photocopies), undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Philip Hofer, French illustrators: Letters between Edwin and Hofer (10 items), 1948 November 5-1949 September 1 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Philip Hofer, French illustrators: Letters between Edwin and Hofer (8 items); typescript copy of "Portrait Engravings in France During the Eighteenth Century", 1949 January 5-1951 July 2, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - French eighteenth century illustrations: Research materials, typescript drafts, 1945-1950 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Goodman, Sidney: Copies of New York Times article on artist Sidney Goodman, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Gravelot: Letters between Edwin and Miss J. Lipman, J. H. Bender, E. Schoor, R. E. Smerian, M. J. Gladstone and F. H. Schonwald, Francena Harris, C. W. David (Librarian of the Free Public Library), the Mayor of Philadelphia, Julian P. Boyd, W. Jackson, F. B. Adams, D. Miner, R. A. Beak, L. G. Coffin, Julain Cain, and G. B. Oldman (23 items); and typescript copy of “Gravelot as Designer of Engraved Portrait Frames,” Print Collectors Quarterly, XXX 41-47 [1950], 1943 January 22-1950 July 5 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Hoopes, P. R.: Typed transcriptions of title pages of 19th century books by P. R. Hoopes, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - "If Shadows Be a Picture's Excellence": Typescript drafts, correspondence, reprint, 1940s (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Judaism: Haym Salomon: A Gentleman of Precision and Integrity, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Judaism: Clippings from The Jewish Exponent, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Benjamin Chew's library: Letter to Edwin from Sara Anne Greene Smith; manuscript notes on Chew's law holdings; Chew's purchases from Mr. Barroll [1778 November 12] and John Dickinson (photocopy); books sent to Chew's Dover, Delaware home [1779 November] (photocopy), 1985 January 3, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Rivington and Brown: Photocopy of 1762 printed catalogue and Edwin's notes, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Library Company of Philadelphia: Photocopy of 1746 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Library Company of Philadelphia: Photocopy of 1775 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Union Library Company: Photocopy of 1754 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Union Library Company: Photocopy of 1764 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Associated Library of Philadelphia: Photocopy of 1775 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Associated Library of Philadelphia: Photocopy of 1798 printed catalogue, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; German books: Offprint of article by R. E. Cazden, "Provision of German Books in America during the 18th Century," Libri, 23(3), 81-108; presentation copy from John McCarthy of 1983 issue of Internationales Archiv fur Sozialgeschichte der deutschen Literatur; photocopies of various Heinrich Miller printed catalogues of books, 1983, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Classical languages in Philadelphia: Typescript of Edwin's "The Classical Languages in Colonial Philadelphia," published in John W. Eadie (Ed.), Classical Tradition in Colonial Philadelphia [1976], circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Belles lettres of colonial Philadelphia: Untitled typescript predecessor of Lyell lectures, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Deism and enlightenment: Photocopy of pages 58-63 of Benjamin Rush's autobiography Travels through Life; photocopy of article by A. H. Scouten, "The Paradox of Deism in Colonial America," Lex et Scientia, 14, 215-228 [1978]; Bodleian Library exhibition catalogue on Edward Young, 1983, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Choice of books in colonial Philadelphia: Typescript predecessor of the Lyell lectures, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Location of books in colonial Philadelphia: Manuscript notes on private inventories of books, shippings records, and catalogues of books for Philadelphia during the colonial period, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Location of books in colonial Philadelphia: Photocopy of title page of 1608 copy of Don Quixote found at the Chapin Library of Williams College and originally in the library of H. Freame; letter to Edwin from Elizabeth Firlingham; list of books (photocopy); Library Company of Philadelphia minutes from 1733 June-1761 December (photocopy); research notes, circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Location of books in colonial Philadelphia: Photocopy of Directions for Proper Choice of Authors to Form a Library [1766]; photocopy excerpt of The Popular Book by James D. Hart [1950]; photocopy excerpt of C. Briden-Baugh, "The Press and Book in Eighteenth Century Philadelphia," Pennsylania Magazine of History and Biography, LXV [1941], circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Location of books in colonial Philadelphia: Typescript of "The Anglo-American Book Trade before 1776: Personal Strategies," by Stephen Botein (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Location of books in colonial Philadelphia: Typescript of "Printed Expertise in Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century American," by Stephen Botein [1984 November 2] (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Pennsylvania State House Library: Letter to Edwin from Whitfield Bell; typescript of letter from Independence National Historical Park, regarding reconstruction of the library of Congress Hall [1961 October 26], circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Colonial law books: Typescript of "Law Books in Colonial Philadelphia" (photocopy), 1968, circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescripts, photocopied research material, letters ("Miscellaneous inventories"), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; William Bradford: Letters to William Bradford from S. Bell [1771 November 2] and Thomas Cadell [1771 November 2] (photocopies); invoices of books shipped to William Bradford [1767 August 10, 1768 August 29, 1769 June 27] (photocopies); invoices for 1767-1769 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; William Bradford: Photocopies of book inventories, 1767-1769, circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; William Bradford: List of books sent from London (photocopy); list of books from Thomas Cadell to William Bradford [1767 August 10] (photocopy); advertisement for books to be sold by William Bradford (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1721-1742 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1742-1749 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1749-1762 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1762-1767 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1767-1770 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1770-1772 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Newspaper advertisements for Philadelphia area book sales, 1772-1776 (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Notes on books in newspaper advertisements and on active bookmen, 1721-1775, circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Inventory of the goods of Ralph Assheton upon his death (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Research notes on John Bartram's holdings and a photocopy of an inventory of his plants, circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Notes on Anthony Bezet's personal letters, circa 1985 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Christ Church Library: Letters between Edwin and W. M. Whitehill, C. Fletcher, and H. E. Sprogell; address given by W. M. Whitehill to the Colonial Society of Massachusetts, 1949 December, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Christ Church Library: Notes on the William White books; manuscript on the early history of the Christ Church Library; typescript of books in a 1912 catalogue of Christ Church, not found; photocopy of 20th century printed catalog, "Books in the Ancient Library", circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Christ Church Library: Photcopy of manuscript by Thomas Bray, "Bibliotheca Provinciales Americanae", circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Christ Church Library: Draft copies of "The First Library of Christ Church," University Hospital Antique Show Journal, 148-151 [1981], circa 1981 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Inventory of George Clymer's book holdings (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: List of law books in John Dickinson's Philadelphia office [1773 May] (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Early settlers and their books: Manuscript predecessor of the Lyell lectures, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Notes on Alexander Graydon, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; David Hall: photocopy of article, R. D. Harlan, "William Strahan's American Book Trade," The Library Quarterly, 31(3) [1961]; notes on David Hall and the colonial book trade; inventories of books sent by David Hall [1766, 1768] (photocopy); newspaper advertisements of books for sale by David Hall [1774, 1756, 1769] (photocopies); photocopies of invoices and notices of import, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Pennsylvania Hospital Library: Draft copy of "The Old Library of the Pennsylvania Hospital" by Whitfield Bell, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Research materials and letters regarding Individual owner inventories (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Research materials and letters regarding Individual owner inventories (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Colonial history books: Edited typescripts on history books in colonial Philadelphia, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Colonial history books: Typescript on history books in colonial Philadelphia, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Transcript of 1687 Pennsbury inventory of goods, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Colonial libraries: Photocopies of articles, T. E. Keys, "The Colonial American Library and the Development of Sectional Differences," The Library Quarterly, VIII(3) [1938]; and E. V. Lamberton, "Colonial Libraries of Pennsylvania," Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, XLII(3) [1918], circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: List of books in the Allegheny College Library formerly owned by James Logan, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Typescript articles on the libraries of James Logan and Isaac Norris, II, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Research materials and typescript articles regarding William Logan and Philip Miller, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Increase Mather: Typescript of "Remains of Mather's Library... purchased by I. Thomas and by him presented to the American Antiqn. Society", circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Increase Mather: Typescript of "Remains of Mather's Library... purchased by I. Thomas and by him presented to the American Antiqn. Society", circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Isaac Norris II: Notes on library holdings; photocopy of note with Alexander Hamilton's autograph; photocopy of page from letterbook [1735-1755]; photocopy of bibliography of books ordered for the Pennsylvania Assembly [1752 March 16], circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; Isaac Norris II: Notes on library holdings and photocopies from letterbook of 1735-55 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Notes on F. D. Pastorius's library and typescript of article, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; John Penn: Notes on John Penn's holdings; letter from Free Library of Philadelphia with a photocopy from Penn's papers; photocopies of newspaper advertisements [1772 May 4-August 6], circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; John Penn: Photocopy of commonplace book listing contents of Penn's library; articles and notes regarding Penn's library, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Notes regarding C. Read, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: List from Library Company of Philadelphia accession books of Benjamin Rush's books and catalog cards (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Inventory of Gilbert Tennant's books (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Inventory of Charles Thompson's books (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Inventory of Zachary Lloyd's books (photocopy), circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography: Photocopies of primary and secondary sources used for research, circa 1985 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; The Book Culture of a Colonial American City: Edited typescripts, circa 1988 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; The Book Culture of a Colonial American City: Proofs, circa 1988 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Lyell Lectures in Bibliography; The Book Culture of a Colonial American City: Typescripts of chapters "They Lived History" and "Lawyers and Law Books", circa 1988 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Montegu, George: Transcription of a 1736 letter to George Montegu, from the Letters of Horace Walpole [1903], edited by Mrs. Paget Toynbee, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Imprint Inventory: Letters between Edwin and C. W. David, L. H. Evans, and E. Campion; typescript proposal, 1947 October 21-1950 November 17 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence, mostly regarding publishing process, 1973-1975 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with the Brooklyn Museum regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with the Huntington Library regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Independence National Historical Park rearding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with the Library of Congress regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with the Mariners Museum regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with the Metropolitan Museum of Art regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with National Portrait Gallery regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Philadelphia Museum of Art regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Smithsonian Institution regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Winterthur Museum regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with Yale University Art Gallery regarding image permissions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Record of expenses, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with University of Pennsylvania regarding image permissions, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with various individuals regarding image permissions, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence with various institutions regarding image permissions, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Contract with William Penn Foundation and publication announcement letters, 1975 December 14 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Letters of congratulations upon publication, correspondence regarding book promotion and errors, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City: Correspondence between John Van Horn and various institutions regarding image permissions for 1990 reissue edition, 1989-1990 (Box 31, Folder 25)